A Guide to the Theodore Shedlovsky papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA130
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Shedlovsky Manuscripts, 1959-1972; 6; 0.9 Cubic Feet
  - "Electromotive Force from Proton Transfer Reactions - A Model for Bioelectric Phenomena", folder 1 of 2 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - "Electromotive Force from Proton Transfer Reactions - A Model for Bioelectric Phenomena", folder 2 of 2 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - "The Ionization Constant of Acetic Acid in Methanol-Water Mixtures at 25° from Conductance Measurements", folder 1 of 2 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - "The Ionization Constant of Acetic Acid in Methanol-Water Mixtures at 25° from Conductance Measurements", folder 2 of 2 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Proposal to the NSF on the "Function of Protons in Solutions", folder 1 of 3 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Proposal to the NSF on the "Function of Protons in Solutions", folder 2 of 3 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Proposal to the NSF on the "Function of Protons in Solutions", folder 3 of 3 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - "Studies on Erythrocyte Sedimentation Rates and Electrophoresis of Normal and Pathological Human Blood" (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Shedlovsky and Mario Goffredi - "Studies of Electrolytic Conductance in Alcohol (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Water Mixtures: Hydrochloric Acid in n-Propanol-Water Mixtures at 15°, 25° and 35°", folder 1 of 2 (Box 20)
  - Shedlovsky & Mario Goffredi - "Studies of Electrolytic Conductance in Alcohol-Water Mixtures: Hydrochloric Acid in n-Propanol-Water Mixtures at 15°, 25° and 35°", folder 2 of 2 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Shedlovsky & Mario Goffredi - "Studies of Electrolytic Conductance in Alcohol-Water Mixtures: Sodium Chloride in n-Propanol-Water Mixtures at 15°, 25° and 35°", folder 1 of 2 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Shedlovsky & Mario Goffredi - "Studies of Electrolytic Conductance in Alcohol-Water Mixtures: Sodium Chloride in n-Propanol-Water Mixtures at 15°, 25° and 35°", folder 2 of 2 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Shedlovsky & Mario Goffredi - "Studies of Electrolytic Conductance in Alcohol-Water Mixtures: The Ionization Constant of Acetic Acid in n-Propanol-Water Mixtures at 15°, 25° and 35°" (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Shedlovsky & H.O. Spivey - "Studies of Electrolytic Conductance in Alcohol-Water Mixtures: Hydrochloric acid, sodium chloride and sodium acetate at 0°, 25° and 35° in Ethanol-Water Mixtures" (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Shedlovsky & H.O. Spivey - "Studies of Electrolytic Conductance in Alcohol-Water Mixtures: The Ionization Constant of Acetic Acid in Ethanol-Water Mixtures at 0°, 25° and 35°" (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 20, Folder 11)
- Manuscripts, 1959-1970; 7; 0.6 Cubic Feet
  Contains manuscripts by others, including Vincent Allfrey, George Janz, and D.J.G. Ives. Some were manuscripts sent to Shedlovsky to review for publication. Also included are manuscripts of a series of book chapters.
  - Borgstrom, George (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Cohen, Hirsh (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Dole, Dr. Vincent (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Hanna, E.M. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Ives, D.J.G.& G.J. Janz: "Microelectrodes & Electrodes in Biology" (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Janz, George (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Kauzmann, Walter (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Klotz, I.M. (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Koefoed, Jørgen, 1956 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Lowenhaupt, Benjamin (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - McHale, John (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Musher, Jeremy (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Pais, A. (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - [Southwell, R.V. (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Steinhaus, H. & S. Trybula, 1959 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Szilard, Leo (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Ware, C.F. (Box 21, Folder 14)
    [Includes correspondence re: reviewing a chapter].
  - Chapter 1 - Ives and Janz (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Chapter 2 - Hills and Ives (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Chapter 3 - Hills and Ives (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Chapter 4 - Janz (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Chapter 5 - Bates (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Chapter 6 - Janz and Ives (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Manuscripts
    - "Moving Boundary Analysis" (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - N.S.F. [National Science Foundation] (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 22, Folder 4)
- Administrative, 1927-1976; 8; 0.8 Cubic Feet
  Contains lecture notes and materials; problems; tests; faculty records; reports to the Dean's Office; student files; student papers; student theses; supply requisition forms; and materials related to the T.I.P. (Thermodynamics of Irreversible Processes) Seminar.
  Arranged in alphabetical order by subject.
  - Lecture notes & materials, 1951-1958 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Lecture materials - Student lectures, 1957 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Lecture notes & materials, 1958, undated (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - [Lecture notes & materials], 1962 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - [Lecture materials: Modern Theories in Inorganic Chemistry (Harry Gray) -Chapter 1 & 2] (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - [Lecture materials: Modem Theories in Inorganic Chemistry (Harry Gray) -Chapter 2 & 3] (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Statistical Mechanics Lectures & Problems (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Thermodynamics problems, 1958 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - [Lecture problems], folder 1 of 2 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - [Lecture problems], folder 2 of 2 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Tests (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Faculty Records, 1927-1956 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Faculty Records, 1957-1976 (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Reports to Dean's Office (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - [Seminars-Chemistry] (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - [Seminar - T.I.P. (Thermodynamics of Irreversible Processes) from V. Dole to T.S.] (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Smullyan Student Files (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Student Paper - Cecil C. Yip (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Student Resumes (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Student Thesis - Cecil C. Yip (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Student Thesis - Charles Carter (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Student Thesis - Richard Cellarius (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Student Thesis - Peter G. Satir (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Supply Requisition Forms, 1968-1969 (Box 24, Folder 3)
- Laboratory Resources, 1940-1972; 9; 0.8 Cubic Feet
  Contains data, tables and graphs, as well as computer printouts from Shedlovsky's lab. Also includes a spiral notebook with lab notes and note cards that contain an index of content for citation purposes.
  - Acetic Acid (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Computer Printouts - Ted Shedlovsky Program (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Conductance, folder 1 of 3 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Conductance, folder 2 of 3 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Conductivity, folder 3 of 3 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Constants of Water-Methanol Mixtures (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Data - Nephrosis Curves (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - "The Determination of Activity Coefficients from the Potentials of Concentration Cells with Transference. I. Sodium Chloride at 25°" (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Electrophoresis-Charts-Spring 1956 Summary, folder 1 of 2 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Electrophoresis-Charts-Spring 1956 Summary, folder 2 of 2 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Ethanol, folder 1 of 6 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Ethanol - 95% HAc, folder 2 of 6 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Ethanol - 20% EtOH-Acetic Acid and HCl, folder 3 of 6 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Ethanol - 60% EtOH-Acetic Acid and HCl, folder 4 of 6 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Ethanol - 80% EtOH-HAc and HCl, folder 5 of 6 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Ethanol - α and β calc. - D, d, η at 25°, folder 6 of 6 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Ethanol-Water (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - The Ionization Constant of Acetic Acid in Water-Methanol Mixtures @ 25° from Conductance Measurements (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - [Ionization Constants, K and Pk, for Acetic Acid in H₂O-CH₃OH Mixtures @ 25°C and 35°C] (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - [Harmonics Chart] (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - [Laboratory Computer Printouts], folder 1 of 2 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - [Laboratory Computer Printouts], folder 2 of 2 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Methanol, folder 1 of 5 (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Methanol, folder 2 of 5 (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Methanol, folder 3 of 5 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - [Methanol], folder 4 of 5 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - [Methanol], folder 5 of 5 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Notes (Data) ca, 1969 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - [Notes cards (index) - Current content] (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Osmotic Coefficients - Ø·η/2·Ø₀ NaCl (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - [Spiral Notebook - untitled & undated] (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - [Miscellaneous] (Box 26, Folder 8)
- Shedlovsky Laboratory Notebooks, 1927-1959; 10; 1.6 Cubic Feet
  Contains bound notebooks containing Shedlovsky's lab work. Includes notes, graphs, tables and data. Some are written chronologically, others by subject including Red Blood Cells, Electrophoresis, Conductance, and Typhus.
  Arranged in chronological order.
  - 1927 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - [Miscellaneous Notes & Graph Paper (found in notebook)] (Box 26, Folder 9A)
  - No. 19, 1928-1929 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - No. 20, 1928-1930 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - No. 21, 1929 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - No. 22, 1929-1930 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - 1930 March- (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - No. 23, 1930-1933 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - 1931- (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - No. 29, 1931 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - No. 38, 1933-1937 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - No. 40, 1934-1951 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - No. 43, 1934-1938 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - No. 47, 1937-1938 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - 1938-1939 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Record Book, 1938-1940 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - No. 49, 1938 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Harvard Computation Book, 1939 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - 1941-1942 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Electrophoresis, Malaria Series, 1943-1944 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - 1943-1944 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Rheumatic Fever Series (#1) - Electrophoresis, 1944 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Electrophoresis II - Miscellaneous - 2/24/44 → 3/2/45 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Work Plan, 1944 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Rheumatic Fever Series (#2) - Electrophoresis, 1944-1945 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - 1944 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Jaundice-Electrophoresis, 1944-1945 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Endocrine Series, 1945 January 10-? (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Red Blood Cell Studies, 1945 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous, 1945 March 13-? (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Typhus, 1945 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - III, 1949-1950 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - 1948 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - 1959 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - MeOH distillation - Conductance of HAc in H₂O-MeOH (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - HCl in H₂O-MeOH, 1955 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - [Undated] (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - [Acetic Acid] [undated] (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - [Undated] (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - [Undated] (Box 30, Folder 7)
- Laboratory Notebooks of Associates, 1930-1969; 11; 3.2 Cubic Feet
  Contains bound notebooks of assistants and colleagues of Shedlovsky. Includes notes, graphs, tables, and data. Individuals include Vincent Allfrey, R.M. Carter, Lorraine Seher, Leo Shedlovsky (brother of Theodore Shedlovsky and also a physical chemist), Olin Spivey, and Catherine Wolowodiuk.
  - V. Allfrey - Electrophoresis - Immunology - ETM Substances, 1945 November 26 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - V. Allfrey - Enzymes - Antigens - Miscellaneous, 1946 June 17 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - V. Allfrey - SERA - Lymphogranuloma (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - A.B - No. 34, 1932-1933 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - A.B - No. 37, 1933 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Louis Belove - R.I.M.R. (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Donald Belcher - No. 42, 1930-1931 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Donald Belcher - No. 24, 1930-1931 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Donald Belcher - No. 36, 1930-1933 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Donald Belcher, 1934 February 1-? (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Joan J. Berdick - Solubility of KSCN and NaCN in: isoamyl alcohol, benzyl alcohol, nitrobenzene, 1947 May 12 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Joan J. Berdick - Concentration cells - EMF measurements Book II (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Joan J. Berdick - Buffers in MeOH-H₂O pH meter liquid function cell, 1953 December 16-1954 March 12 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Joan J. Berdick - MeOH-H₂O buffers Hydrogen electrodes, 1954 March 17-? (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - R.J. Best, 1943 September-? (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - R.M. Carter, 1954 September 2-December 31 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - R.M. Carter, 1955 January 4-June 18 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - R.M. Carter - Book III, 1955 May 19-December 14 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - R.M. Carter - Book IV, 1955 December 12-1957 February (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - R.M. Carter, 1956 April- (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - R.M. Carter - Dr. Mac Innes Lab (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - R.M. Carter Dr. Shedlovsky Lab, 1957 February- (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Joseph Greenspan, 1942-1943 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Joseph Greenspan - Notes, Abstracts, Extracts (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Joseph Greenspan, 1942-1945 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Joseph Greenspan - Notes, Abstracts, Extracts (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Joseph Greenspan - Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Joseph Greenspan, 1942-1943 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Baiba Grube, 1964 December 21-? (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Baiba Grube, 1968 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Baiba Grube, 1969 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Leonore Hess - Book #1 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Leonore Hess - Book #2 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Leonore Hess - Book #3 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - R.L. Kay- Titrations (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - R.L. Kay, 1943 August 12-1944 October (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - R.L. Kay, 1944 November-? (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - S. Levinson - Notebook No. 1 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - S. Liotta - Lab Record (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - S. Liotta, 1943 May 4-? (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - S. Liotta- (USN-A), 1945 March-? (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - E. Pulman - Dr. Shedlovsky Bk. #1, 1960 June 6 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Lorraine Seher - Dr. Shedlovsky Book #1, 1960 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Lorraine Seher - Dr. Shedlovsky Book #2, 1960-1961 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Lorraine Seher - Dr. Shedlovsky Book #3, 1961 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Lorraine Seher - Dr. Shedlovsky Book #4, 1961-1962 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Lorraine Seher - Dr. Shedlovsky Book#5, 1962 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Lorraine Seher - Dr. Shedlovsky Book #6, 1962 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Lorraine Seher - Dr. Shedlovsky Book #7, 1962-1963 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Lorraine Seher - Dr. Shedlovsky Book #8 [1963-] (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Lorraine Seher - Flexner A8 - Primary Data, 1963 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Lorraine Seher - Flexner A8 - Purification & Preparation of Solvents & Stock Solutions (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Lorraine Seher - Flexner A8 - Primary Data #2, 1963-1964 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Lorraine Seher - Flexner A8 - Calculations Book #9, 1963 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Lorraine Seher - Flexner A8 - III, 1964 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Leo Shedlovsky - Analyses, 1939 September 29 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - O. Spivey - Conductance Measurements - Data, 1962-1963 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - O. Spivey - Flexner A8 - Calculations, 1962-1963 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - O. Spivey, 1963 May 27-? (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - D. Taub - R.I.M.R., 1943 February 3-? (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Catherine Wolowodiuk - Dr. Shedlovsky's Lab, 1964-1965 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Catherine Wolowodiuk - Dr. Shedlovsky's Lab, 1965-1966 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Catherine Wolowodiuk - Primary Data Book III, 1966 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Catherine Wolowodiuk - Primary Data Book IV, 1966 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Catherine Wolowodiuk - Flexner A8, 1966 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Catherine Wolowodiuk - Flexner A8, 1967-1968 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Catherine Wolowodiuk, 1968 March-? (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - H.H. Uhlig (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - [Unnamed], 1956 February (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - [Unnamed], 1962-1964 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - [Unnamed] - Preparation of Stock Solutions, 1965-1966 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - [Unnamed] - Solvents & Stock Solutions, 1966 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - [Unnamed] - Solvents & Solutions, 1967 (Box 38, Folder 9)
- Reprints, 1951-1960; 12; 0.3 Cubic Feet
  Contains reprints of Shedlovsky and colleagues some of which have been annotated or signed. Includes reprints in Russian and German. Some include miscellaneous notes within their pages.
  Arranged in alphabetical order (Shedlovsky reprints first).
  - T. Shedlovsky - "Conductometry" (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - T. Shedlovsky - 'The Determination of the Ionization Constant of Acetic Acid, at 25°, from Conductance Measurements." [Shedlovsky & MacInnes] (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - T. Shedlovsky - "The Electrolytic Conductivity of Some Uni-Univalent Electrolytes in Water at 25°" (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - T. Shedlovsky - "The Relation of Electrochemistry to Medicine" (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - T. Shedlovsky - "Symposium on Electrochemical Constants", 1951 September 19-21 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - T. Shedlovsky - "Symposium on Solutions of Electrolytes", 1954 June 16-18 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Camoйлов, О. Я - [In Russian], 1955 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Clews, C.J.B. - "The Electrical Conductivity of Strong Electrolytes and its Variation with Temperature" (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Ecйн, O.A. - [In Russian], 1956 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Фpмқйн, A.H., et al. - [In Russian], 1956 (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Grim, Eugene & Karl Sollner - "True Anomalous Osmosis in Multi-Solute Model Membrane Systems" (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Katchalsky, A., et al. - "Hydrogen Bonding & Ionization of Carboxylic Acids in Aqueous Solutions." [also miscellaneous notes] (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - Kaufman, Samuel & C.R. Singleterry - "The Critical Range for Micelle Formation by an Oil Dispersible Soap in Hydrocarbon Solvent" (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - Kelbg, G. - [In German], 1959 (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - Kolin, Alexander - "Isoelectric Spectra & Mobility Spectra: A New Approach to Electrophonetic Separation" (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - Kraus, Charles A. - "Electrolytes: From Dilute Solutions to Fused Salts." [also miscellaneous notes] (Box 39, Folder 16)
  - Kretchmer, Jerome - "Asbestos Content of Consumer Talcs in New York City" (Box 39, Folder 17)
  - La Mer, Victor K. - ["Rough Draft"] (Box 39, Folder 18)
  - Loewi, Otto - "An Autobiographical Sketch" (Box 39, Folder 19)
  - McCulloch, Warren S. - "Where is Fancy Bred? " (Box 39, Folder 20)
  - [Miscellaneous Reprints & Notes] (Box 39, Folder 21)
  - Ottиck, O. - [In Russian], 1960 (Box 39, Folder 22)
  - Overbeek, J. - "Electric Conductivity & Transference of Alkali Albuminates" (Box 39, Folder 23)
  - Overbeek, J. - "Interpretation of the Conductance & Transference of Bovine Serum Albumin Solutions" (Box 39, Folder 24)
  - Pauling, Linus - "Modern Structural Chemistry" (Box 39, Folder 25)
- Negatives & Photos, 1930-1966; 13; 0.6 Cubic Feet
  Contains negatives from Shedlovsky's lab and lectures. Also includes photos and negatives from the RU Concerts.
  - Shedlovsky, 1930 (Box 39, Folder 26)
  - Shedlovsky, 1931 (Box 39, Folder 27)
  - Shedlovsky, 1933 (Box 39, Folder 28)
  - Shedlovsky, 1934 (Box 39, Folder 29)
  - MacFadyen, 1934-1937 (Box 39, Folder 30)
  - Shedlovsky, 1935 (Box 39, Folder 31)
  - Shedlovsky, 1936 (Box 39, Folder 32)
  - Bergmann, 1937 (Box 39, Folder 33)
  - Shedlovsky, 1937 (Box 39, Folder 34)
  - Shedlovsky, 1938 (Box 39, Folder 35)
  - Negatives
    - Van Slyke & MacFadyen, 1938 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - MacFadyen, 1939 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Shedlovsky, 1940 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Shedlovsky, 1941 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Shedlovsky, 1942 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Shedlovsky, 1942 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Shedlovsky, 1943 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Shedlovsky, 1944 (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Photos, 1945 (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - Shedlovsky, 1945 (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - "Electrophonetic patterns", 1948 1951 1959 (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - "Protochemical", 1951 (Box 40, Folder 12)
    - Mixed Solvent pH, 1954 1955 1957 (Box 40, Folder 13)
    - HAc in H₂O-CH₃OH - R. Kay, 1954 1957 (Box 40, Folder 14)
    - "Saturated Salt - bisolvent EMF", 1954-1962 (Box 40, Folder 15)
      [Includes photos of apparatus/glassware].
    - "Mixed Solvent HAc (Trieste Paper)", 1959 (Box 40, Folder 16)
    - Musical concert, 1960 November 2 (Box 40, Folder 17)
    - Shedlovsky, 1964 (Box 40, Folder 18)
    - Shedlovsky, 1966 (Box 40, Folder 19)
  - Photos
    - Prints - miscellaneous (Box 40, Folder 20)
    - Prints - Technical (Box 40, Folder 21)
- Audio Tapes, 1965-1974; 14; 0.8 Cubic Feet
  Contains magnetic reels of audio from various RU Concerts and performances. Also includes recordings from the Conference on Scientific Aspects of Musical String Instruments and other lectures. Mostly 7" reels, some 5" reels.
  Conditions Governing Access
  RAC is unable to provide access to obsolete media, due to the specialized equipment necessary to facilitate playback. When feasible, a digital surrogate may be created via special order. All applicable charges will apply. See RAC Head of Archival Services or RAC Head of Digital Programs for details.
  - Leopold Aver - Private Recording - Italy - 7½ IPS (Box 41, Folder 1)
    RAC is unable to provide access to the original item, due to the specialized equipment necessary to facilitate playback. When feasible, a digital surrogate may be created via special order. All applicable charges will apply. See RAC Head of Archival Services or RAC Head of Digital Programs for details.
  - Conference on Scientific Aspects of Musical String Instruments - Part I (voice) - R.U. - 24 May 1968-Friday (9:30am-1:00pm) - Caspary Auditorium- Recorded at l ⅞ IPS - Sides 1 & 2 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Conference on Scientific Aspects of Musical String Instruments - R.U. - 24 May 1968 (Friday) - Part II - Recorded at 3¾ IPS (music and voice) - Caspary Auditorium (2:00-3:15pm) - Side 1 - The Chamber Players, 1968 May 24 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Conference on Scientific Aspects of Musical String Instruments - 24 May 1968 (Friday) - Part III - Rockefeller University Rm 1A & B (voice & music) -Recording Speed - l ⅞ IPS (3:00pm - 5:45 pm) - Side 1 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Loren Hollander, 1965 May 21 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Forum-2/8/66 - John McGahern (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Lectures in Art - Art of the Renaissance in Sicily - Maria Accascuna - Prof. of Art History (University of Messina) - Caspary Auditorium - The Rockefeller University - 14- 3¾ IPS - Side 1, April 1969 8:30pm (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Young Violinists from Japan - Juilliard School of Music, 1964 March 12 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - RU Concerts - #1 - Eric Wilner: flute - Gui-Michel: caillot, piano - Fr. Martin: ballade - Bach: Sonata in B minor (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - RU Concerts - Chamber Players - Caspary Auditorium, Friday 1968 May 24 at 8:30pm (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - RU Concerts - A Concert of Chamber Music in Memory of Hans Thatcher Clarke - Caspary Auditorium, Monday 1974 May 6 at 8:00pm (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - RU Concerts - Excerpts from The Legend of the Rood - By Tom Wagner - As Performed by The Wagner Renaissance Opera Company - 7½ IPS halftrack stereo - Copyright Thomas Wagner (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - RU Concerts - The Legend of the Rood - Recorded Caspary Hall May 6, 1972 - 3.75 IPS - 1st Half → A Side - 2nd Half → B Side, folder 1 of 3 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - RU Concerts - The Legend of the Rood - Recorded Caspary Hall May 6, 1972 - 3¾ IPS - 1st Half → A Side - 2nd Half → B Side, folder 2 of 3 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - RU Concerts - The Legend of the Rood, 1972 May 6; folder 3 of 3 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - [Unlabeled 5" Reel] (Box 42, Folder 8)
- Slides, 1948-1949, undated; 15; 0.6 Cubic Feet
  Contains glass lantern slides (#s 1800-62 _), glass plates, and 2" x 2" slides.
  Arranged by type and number.
  - Glass Lantern Slides - #s 1800s-3000s (Box 43)
  - Glass Lantern Slides - #s 3000s-62__ and "Red Diagrams", Apparatus, and Miscellaneous (Box 44)
  - 6 Glass Plates by Dr. Van Dyke 38 2" × 2" slides [61-, 62-, 66-1574 (I-III), 66-1926 (I-II)], 1948-1949 (Box 45)
  - 27 2" x 2" slides [3000, 4000, 5700, 5800, 6000, 7000, 9000] (Box 46)
- Artifacts, undated; 16; 0.8 Cubic Feet
  Contains artifacts including an animal horn; role of gold wire; hand stamps; name tags; business card; tiles from Caspary Hall; rolls of unidentified 35mm film; A Get Well Poster; and a World Academy of Art & Science Certificate.
  No order.
  - (3) Light Filters - 2" (Box 47)
  - Animal Horn (Box 48)
  - Roll of wire [99.99% Au- 0.007"-5ft.] - 11/25/55 (Box 49)
  - T. Shedlovsky hand stamps (Box 50)
  - Science diagram hand stamp (Box 51)
  - Science diagram hand stamps (Box 52)